The frontend cloud wouldn't be
complete without addressing data.
As frontend frameworks continue
moving towards the server and the
edge, it's time to bring Vercel's
developer experience to databases.
You want a database that just works with
the modern primitives of Vercel, like
serverless and edge functions, and it's
built on open standards and protocols.
Today we're announcing databases on
Vercel powered by the best infrastructure
providers to make that dream a reality.
Vercel Blob makes it easy
to store files in the cloud.
It's fast, easy, and efficient.
We've designed a simple, yet
powerful API for storage, built
entirely on top of web standards.
This means that your users can easily
upload files or attachments of any size.
You can call the Vercel Blob API
securely from your edge functions.
It accepts a web stream that returns
an immutable URL you can expose to
your visitors or put into storage.
One of the most common tools I
like to reach for is a general
purpose key value store.
Vercel KV makes serverless Redis
easy and durable to quickly implement
features like rate limiting, session
management, and application states.
Reimagining storage frontend first
means creating a developer experience
where you don't need to manage scaling,
instant sizes or Redis clusters.
It's truly serverless.
Our lightweight, Redis compatible
SDK works from your edge or
serverless function and scales
infinitely with your traffic, and
you can use all your favorite tools.
Like the Redis CLI.
Oh, and it's really fast.
We love Redis, but sometimes
you want the full power of SQL.
Vercel Postgres delivers on the dream
of serverless SQL for the frontend
cloud, we've integrated the most
innovative Postgres infrastructure, so
you don't have to manage connections or
manually scale Postgres in the cloud.
Let that sink in.
This means that you can now
easily and securely query data
directly from your React server
components and not just querying.
You can also insert, update or
delete data with server actions.
Head to vercel.com/storage to start
building with Postgres, KV and Blob.